Please wait! I'm getting on!
等等 我要上车！
BRANCH MANAGING DEPARTMENT BRANCH INSPECTION - MAI HANASAKI
（分行管理部稽核班 花琦舞）
I made it.
赶上了
-Want to come to my place tonight? -What?
-晚上要去我那里吗？ -什么？
-My mom's not home today. -Really?
-我妈今天不在家 -真的吗？
-Your eyelash. -Oh?
-你的睫毛 -哦？
-Thanks. -You're welcome.
-谢谢 -别客气
-Are you okay? -Yeah. Thank you.
-你还好吗？ -还好 谢谢
-Okay?
-还好
Ouch…
哎呀
They're so lucky.
她们真幸运
I wonder where I can find my Mr. Right.
我去哪里找我的真命天子呢？
I found it.
我找到了
Good morning, Mr. Shibasaki.
芝崎次长 早安
Good morning, Hanasaki.
花琦 早
BRANCH MANAGING DEPARTMENT ASSISTANT GM TAIICHI SHIBASAKI
（分行管理部 芝崎太一次长）
That's yours, right?
那是你的吧？
Thank you very much.
不好意思 真是谢谢您
Looks like you're having a leisurely morning.
看起来你早上挺悠闲的
What?
什么？
Oh! I have to go. Excuse me.
抱歉 我得走了
She's full of energy.
她真是精力充沛
Excuse me! I'm getting on!
抱歉 我要进去
Good morning,
早安
Mr. Shindo, Mr. Kodama.
真藤部长 儿玉次长
CORPORATE PLANNING DIVISION ASSISTANT GM NAOKI KODAMA
（常务执行董事 真藤毅）
Branch Inspection.
稽核班的
I'm Hanasaki.
我是花琦
You're working hard.
你工作真努力
Not at all. I'm only getting used to it.
没有 只是渐渐习惯了
I'm thankful that you've accepted this job
我很感谢你为了我们银行
that nobody wants to do, for the sake of our bank.
接受这份没人想做的工作
Not at all.
请别这么说
But I will do my best.
不过我会尽全力的
Banks have their own unique customs and views,
银行有自己独特的习惯和看法
so it must be hard for a young lady like yourself.
像你这样的年轻女子一定不容易
No… Oh, but…
不会啦 不过…
The traditional views of the bank are a little stuffy
银行传统的看法是有一点沉闷
and old fashioned sometimes…
而且有时候太过时了
I'm sorry. I couldn't resist.
抱歉 我按耐不住
-Work hard. -Yes. Thank you.
-认真工作 -我会的 谢谢
BRANCH INSPECTION
（分行稽核班）
-Good morning.
-早安
All right. I made it on time.
还好 我准时到了
You can rush in here, but there's nothing to do.
你可以冲进来 但是没事做
What? There's no inspection today?
什么？今天不用稽核吗？
It's a good sign for us to be bored.
我们无聊是好事
What?
什么？
Because it means there are no problems at the branches.
那就表示分行没有问题
I see… but we're not the police.
懂了 可是我们不是警察
Unlike my time at the branch,
不像我在分行的时候
I have time to enjoy my coffee like this.
我现在有时间像这样享受咖啡
It's not so bad.
感觉还不赖
I can't handle staying still
我还是无法忍受
in a quiet place like this.
待在这么安静的地方
That's why being a teller was the perfect job for me.
所以还是当柜员最适合我
You're too young.
你太年轻了
Mr. Soma,
相马先生
you're not that old either.
你也没那么老呀
Hey. I never said that I was old…
喂 我可从没说过我老
Hello. Branch Inspection.
您好 稽核班
No, it's not. Yes. Goodbye.
不是 对 再见
What was it?
怎么了？
-It was a wrong number. -I see.
-拨错号码 -这样啊
It's too quiet.
太安静了
-Should I sing something? -No, thank you.
-要我唱歌吗？ -不用 谢谢
The bank is stuffy and old fashioned, huh?
银行沉闷又过 时吗？
That female employee doesn't know anything.
那个女职员什么都不懂
She just happened to solve a big incident recently,
她只是最近刚好解决一个大事件
so she's getting ahead of herself.
才会自以为是
Then you should teach her.
那么你就应该教教她
Yes?
是
Normally, a Branch Inspector
通常一个稽核员
is only supposed to solve small issues within the branch.
应该只解决分行内的小问题
They're almost non-existent in this organization.
他们在这个组织中几乎不存在
Take care of it.
去处理好
Yes!
是
The branch data has been organized,
分行的数据整理好了
all the documents for disposal were shredded,
废文件都扔进碎纸机了
and we cleaned the office.
办公室也打扫了
There's nothing to do tomorrow.
明天没事做了
Dad, what's wrong?
爸 怎么了？
-I haven't been feeling well. -Really?
-我感觉不太对 -真的吗？
I feel uneasy.
感觉心神不宁
My pot broke, I'm out of sweet sake, and my knife is blunt.
我的锅破了 甜酒没了 刀也钝了
That's not your health.
不是你健康的问题
What are those pills?
-那是什么药丸？ -嗯？
They're supplements.
营养补品
You bought this many?
你买了这么多？
I get one free when I buy three.
买三送一
I see.
这样啊
"Araiso no ko"? Does this work?
“荒矶之子”？有效吗？
Apparently, some type of extract from seaweed.
当然 这是某种海藻抽取物
-It's good for somewhere in the body. -How vague.
-对人体某些地方有帮助 -不清不楚的
All of my customers take this.
我的顾客都吃这个
So I'm sure it works.
我相信它有效
You always fall for these online health commercials.
网络上的健康广告你总是信以为真
But they never last.
可是从来都维持不了
-That's not true. -Yes, it is.
-才不是那样 -就是
Acupressure sandals, knee brace,
脚底按摩拖鞋、护膝
balance ball, and exercise steps. They're all dusty.
平衡球、健身梯 全都沾灰尘了
And the inversion table is just a clothing rack.
还有那个健身车只当衣架用了
-I'll use it someday. -I wonder.
-有一天我会用的 -是这样吗？
-One, two, one, two. -It won't last long.
-一、二… -撑不久的
I see.
原来如此
Please leave it up to me.
这点请交给我吧
I'm counting on you.
就靠你了
Kayabacho and Aoyama.
茅场町和青山
Mr. Shindo is very frustrated because two Branch Managers
真藤先生为了 两个分行长的事非常郁闷
from the Shindo faction have been dismissed one after another.
因为真藤派系的人接连被开除
There is lots of work to do at my branch,
我的分行工作很多
so I'm sure they'll give up in one day.
我相信总会让他们会屈服的
I'm glad to hear that.
很高兴听你这样说
KAMATA BRANCH BRANCH MANAGER SUGA
（蒲田分行长 须贺）
I'll brand them as useless workers
我会让他们背上无用人员的污名
and send them back to you.
然后送还给你
I look forward to it.
我非常期待
Mr. Kodama, if this goes well…
儿玉先生 如果事情进行顺利…
I will put in a word with Mr. Shindo
当然 我会对真藤部长说
so that you can go to the department of your choice,
下次调动时
during the next transfer.
你就可以进你想进的部门
Thank you.
那就谢谢你了
How long has this been collecting dust?
这个积灰尘多久了？
Hello, it's Hanasaki.
喂 我是花琦
I just got a call from Mr. Shibasaki.
我刚刚接到芝崎先生的电话
They want us to go to the Kamata Branch for two days early next week.
说要我们下周一早去蒲田分行两天
-For inspection? -No, it's for support.
-去稽核吗？ -不是 是去支援
Support?
支援？
You'll be a teller.
你不是柜员吗？
What? A teller?
是说要当柜员吗？
Yeah.
对
How annoying. This is not our job as Branch Inspectors.
真烦人 这不是稽核员的工作
I got it!
我知道了
See you later. Good night.
再见 晚安
What's wrong with her?
她有什么问题啊？
Yes!
太好了
I can work as a teller for the first time in a long while.
好久没做柜员的工作了！
All right!
太棒了
Unbelievable.
难以置信
Mr. Shibasaki should turn down jobs that are not
芝崎先生应该拒绝
associated with branch inspection.
与稽核分行无关的工作
But it was a request from the Branch Manager, right?
可是那是分行长的要求 不是吗？
They probably have high hopes for us.
他们大概对我们抱有高度期望
High hopes? For us? For what?
抱有高度期望？为什么？
I guess so… but what kind of person is the Branch Manager?
我猜也是 不过那位分行长是怎样的人？
He's an elite from headquarters
他是总部来的精英
and it's only been a year since he went to the Kamata Branch.
而且他去蒲田分行才一年
I see.
这样啊
But ever since he took over, their numbers have been declining.
不过自从他接手后 他们的数字就往下掉
He was always harsh on his subordinates,
他对下属总是很严苛
but I hear he's getting worse these days.
我听说他最近更是变本加厉
-I see. -Oh.
-这样啊 -对了
And he's from the Shindo faction.
而且他是真藤派的
-Again? -Yes.
-又来了？ -对
KAMATA BRANCH
（蒲田分行）
Hanasaki.
花琦
Don't get riled up.
这次不要被激怒
I know. If I want to say something,
我知道 如果我想说什么
I'll breathe in.
我会吸气
Promise me you'll do that.
这次真的拜托你了
-Yes. -Where's your smile?
-是 -你的笑容呢？
Can't you smile a little more warmly?
你不能笑得更亲切点吗？
Then show me how to do it.
那么你示范给我看啊
What? I guess I have no other choice.
什么啊？我猜我别无选择了
Can I take a picture of that?
可以让我拍张照吗？
BRANCH MANAGER'S OFFICE
（分行长室）
So you're the Branch Inspectors.
你们就是稽核班？
Yes, it's nice to meet you.
是 幸会
We will do our best.
我们会尽全力帮忙
Your best?
尽全力？
Yes.
是
That's what people say when they cut corners.
那是投机取巧的人说的话
That's not what I meant.
不 我不是那个意思
We heard that we were called here
听说我们被叫来这里
because you personally requested us.
是您个人的要求
It wasn't a request.
那不是要求
We're in a tight spot right now because
我们目前人力吃紧
one of our tellers quit, and the Deputy Manager is at training.
因为一个柜员辞职 代理课长又正在受训
So I asked for someone who's free and bored.
所以我请求有空又无聊的人过来
By the way, our branch is very busy
顺带一提 我们分行非常忙碌
so be prepared.
请做好心理准备
It will be difficult for people like you guys who have been away from action.
对于你们这种 清闲很久的人会很辛苦
No one will take pity and help you even if you cry.
就算你哭 也没有人会怜悯和帮忙的
I will do my very best.
我会尽我最大能力的
-Just as I always do. -Step back.
-一如既往 -退后
How dare he think that I would cry.
他竟敢认为我会哭
All right.
很好
If we continue this way, we won't meet our budget.
要是这样继续下去 我们将无法达成预算
The F Block is certain to place last again.
Ｆ区肯定再度垫底
Why isn't there
为什么就没有一个人
a single person who can live up to my expectations?
能够不辜负我的期望呢？
Listen carefully.
仔细听好了
We don't need incompetent people at this branch!
这个分行不需要无能的人！
Finance Department.
融资课
I've been bringing in major clients,
我一直带主要客户进来
but what are you doing?
但是你们在做什么？
Don't show your face here until you bring in a new loan account.
在带来新的贷款帐户之前 别在这里露脸！
Yes, sir.
是！
Sales Division.
营业课
I'm not expecting you to raise profits.
我不指望你们提升获利
Just don't go into minus.
只要别变成亏钱
Listen. Just don't make any mistakes.
听好 不要出任何差错
-Yes, sir. -Louder!
-是！ -大声点！
Yes, sir.
是！
Oh, these Branch Inspectors from headquarters
这两位总部来的稽核班成员
have come all the way here
大老远来到这里
to help us out with administrative support.
帮忙我们做行政支援
They usually inspect branches.
他们通常负责稽核分行
Hopefully they will be of some help.
希望他们能帮上一点忙
Hanasaki, you will work as a teller.
花琦 你当柜员
Yes, sir.
是
Soma, you'll be in the lobby
相马 你到大厅
to direct the customers.
指引客户
What?
什么？
Nice to meet you.
麻烦大家了
I'm getting excited.
我好兴奋
ATTENDANT
（接待员）
Why am I doing this?
我为什么要做这个？
Nice to meet you.
麻烦你了
The battle is about to begin.
好 战争即将开始
Battle?
战争？
Welcome.
欢迎光临
I will pass out ticket numbers, so please stand in line.
我会发号码牌 请排队
Excuse me. I will pass out the ticket number.
抱歉 我会发号码牌
Welcome.
欢迎光临
Welcome. Good morning.
欢迎光临 早安
-Wow. -Please.
-哇！ -请在这
Pick up your ticket number here.
取号
Welcome.
欢迎光临
Please hold onto this number and take a seat.
请收好这个号码 稍坐一下
I was wondering who they would be,
我还在想他们是何方神圣
but they ended up being a cheeky young girl and a man who's spaced out.
结果只是一个厚脸皮的女孩 和一个精神恍惚的男人
Yes, sir.
是
Load them with work. Don't show them mercy.
给他们大量工作 别心软
Yes, sir.
是的 分行长
It'll be too much for them to handle.
他们会招架不了
We have some customers that are hard to deal with.
我们有一些客户很难搞
How long are you going to make us wait?
你要让我们等多久？
How long do you think I've been waiting?
你知道我们等多久了吗？
I'm sorry.
非常抱歉
I'm processing a transaction for the previous customer.
我正在处理上一位客户的业务
-Please wait a little longer. -No, I won't.
-请再等一下 -我不等
What's wrong with this bank?
这家银行是怎么回事？
You guys are working too slow.
你们的工作速度太慢了
I'm very sorry. I'll try to work faster.
非常抱歉 我会努力快一点
What?
什么？
Please wait.
请稍等
Fine then.
真是的
Thank you.
感谢您
Thank you for waiting, Mr. Arakawa.
荒川先生 谢谢您 久等了
Please confirm this.
请您确认
My legs are swollen.
我腿肿了
Oh, Mr. Kaneda.
金田先生
-I'll help you. -Thank you.
-我来帮忙 -谢谢
Thank you.
多谢你了
It must be tough every day,
每天都不容易吧？
to be helping out customers and running other tasks at the same time.
要协助客户 同时又要忙别的工作
I'm forcing myself to keep going.
我强迫自己继续做下去
That's amazing.
真厉害
Our tellers are very competent,
我们的柜员能力虽然很好
but Ms. Hanasaki has wonderful customer service.
不过花琦小姐的客户服务非常棒
They have to deal with both nice customers and difficult customers.
好客户和坏客户她们都要面对
She once told me that
她曾经跟我说
she never distinguishes her customers.
她从不区别她的客户
She has the same attitude towards everyone.
她对每个人都是一样的态度
Even her boss.
就连对老板也一视同仁
I'll remember that.
我会记住的
But please don't tell her that.
不过请这件事请别告诉她
She'll get carried away.
她会得意忘形
Why are you resting?
你们为什么在休息？
Even if you're only a part-timer,
就算你只是兼职的
we don't need unmotivated workers.
我们也不需要缺乏动力的员工
I apologize.
很抱歉
It's not your break time yet.
你的休息时间还没到
You're right.
是的
Thank you for waiting.
谢谢您耐心等待
Have fun at your grandchild's birthday party.
祝您在孙子的生日派对玩得愉快
-Thank you. -Take care.
-谢谢 -保重
Thank you.
谢谢您
CALL
（叫号）
Number 212.
212号
Transfer and tax receipt.
转帐和报税
TRANSFER
（转帐）
Welcome.
欢迎光临
Thank you for waiting.
谢谢您耐心等候
Please come again.
请再度光临
Wow.
哇！
She's really meant to be a teller, huh?
她还真是当柜员的料
-How's that female teller? -Well…
-那个女柜员怎么样了？ -那个…
Welcome, Mr. Takeuchi.
武内先生 欢迎
Hello, Branch Manager Suga.
你好 须贺分行长
How can we help you today?
今天有什么我能效劳的？
I have a few transfers to make.
我有几笔钱要转
I can take that.
交给我
Please have a seat.
请坐 稍等一下
Thank you.
谢谢
Hey you, do this first.
你先做这个
I'm working in order.
我是照顺序做的
I told you to do this first.
我要你先做这个
Mr. Takeuchi is an important customer.
武内先生是重要客户
Then I think it would be best to process this in the back.
那样的话 我认为最好在里面处理
Because all the other customers have been waiting in line.
因为所有客户都在排队
I told you to do it right now!
我要你立刻做！
Please don't worry.
别担心 分行长
They're working in order.
她们是按照顺序的
-I'm very sorry. -Not at all.
-真的非常抱歉 -没关系
-I'm sorry. -It's okay.
-很抱歉
-Please have a seat. -Yes.
-请稍坐 -好
Welcome.
欢迎光临
The rest is fine.
其余的都很好
So fast!
这么快！
-It's balanced. -That was fast!
-结算无误 -好快！
BALANCE
（结算）
Wow.
哇！
-It's balanced. -Okay.
-结算无误 -好
It's balanced.
结算无误
-It's balanced. -Okay.
-结算无误 -好
TOTAL BALANCE AT TELLER BALANCED
（总窗口收支结算无误）
Everything is balanced.
全部结算无误
-Thank you.
-辛苦大家了 -辛苦了
I'm done.
完成了！
I processed 105 customers today. No wonder it was so busy.
我今天处理了105位客户 难怪那么忙
I did 96.
我是96位
I'm sorry, I only did 84.
抱歉 我才84位
What? Ms. Hanasaki, you did 143?
什么？花琦 你服务了143位？
I gave it my all because it's been
我用尽了全力
a while since I've done this.
因为我好久没做柜员的工作了
Wow.
真厉害！
It's nothing.
没什么啦
Didn't you give them work to do?
你没给他们工作吗？
Yes.
有
I directed all the difficult customers to her,
我把所有难搞的客户都带去给她
so she should've given up already but…
她应该早就要放弃了
she's more detailed and faster than our experienced tellers.
可是她比我们经验丰富的柜员 更仔细、速度更快
-Why are you impressed? -I'm sorry!
-你干嘛那么佩服她？ -对不起
Think of something else.
想想别的办法
If they leave here unscathed,
要是他们从这里全身而退
I won't be able to face Mr. Shindo!
我无法向真藤先生交代
Make sure you knock them down tomorrow!
你明天务必击垮他们
Yes, sir.
是
This restaurant is far away from the branch,
这间餐厅距离分行非常远
so we don't have to worry about bumping into co-workers or customers.
不必担心遇到同事或客户
Okay.
太好了
Cheers!
干杯
We can complain all we want here.
在这里我们可以尽情抱怨
That's important.
那很重要
That branch is so somber and stressful.
这间分行好严肃 压力好大
I'm glad you agree.
你也这么想？
The atmosphere changes when Branch Manager walks in.
分行长一进来气氛就变了
Yes, it does.
没错
He's always frustrated because
他总是脾气那么暴躁
our branch isn't producing good results.
因为我们分行没有做出好业绩
It gives us anxiety because he's always
他老在主楼层走来走去
walking around the main floor.
那让我们更焦虑
It's as if he's looking over our shoulders.
好像他在偷看我们
Wouldn't that cause you to make mistakes?
那不会让你们出错吗？
-Yes! -Right?
-会 -对吧？
Let's drink all we want today
我们今天就尽情畅饮
and release our stress!
纾解压力吧
Cheers.
干杯
-That was a long day. -Yes.
-今天真是辛苦了 -是啊
Delicious.
好吃
I'm glad I brought you here.
我很高兴带你来这里
This is excellent.
这里太棒了
I had made a note of this place as somewhere to visit
老实说 我有做笔记
in Kamata. See?
记录了来蒲田一定要去的地方 你看
Oh, that's good to know.
原来如此
The sashimi sounds good too.
这里的生鱼片好像也很不错
I want the potato salad,
我想吃马铃薯沙拉
and the simmered beef and tofu too.
还有炖牛肉和豆腐
Ms. Hanasaki, you were so cool today.
花琦小姐 你今天超酷的
With Mr. Takeuchi, right?
对武内先生 对吧？
The Branch Manager's face was hilarious.
分行长的表情好好笑
It sure was.
没错
-Is Mr. Takeuchi a longtime customer? -No.
-武内先生是老客户吗？ -不是
He's the president of an IT company in Shinagawa.
他是品川区一家 信息科技公司的总裁
He recently built a house near our branch, and that's when he
他最近在我们分行附近盖了房子
became our customer.
才成了我们的客户
Then why does he get special treatment?
那他为什么受到特殊待遇？
He's planning to move his company near the branch,
他打算把公司搬到分行附近
so the Branch Manager wants him.
所以分行长想拉拢他
He wants them to use our bank.
让我们成为他们的主要银行
Mr. Takeuchi's company apparently makes two billion yen a year.
毕竟武内先生的公司 一年赚二十亿日元
I see, so that's what it is.
原来是这么回事
So you finalized the plans to relocate your office?
所以你最后决定要搬迁办公室了吗？
Yes. I believe my employees will be using your bank after we relocate.
对 我相信搬迁之后 我们的员工会使用你们银行
And as for the other thing we discussed…
还有我们讨论过的另一件事
Oh, about our main bank?
是关于我们的主要银行吧？
Yes.
是
We've been with Hakusui Bank for a long time,
我们和白水银行合做很久了
but there's no office in Kamata.
不过他们在蒲田没有办事处
I think I will be moving over
我想我们会换到你们这里
to Tokyo Daiichi Bank.
换到东京第一银行
-Really? -Yes.
-真的吗？ -是的
Thank you very much.
太感谢了
I'd like to set everything up at once with
我想一次搞定所有东西
direct deposits and things like that.
直接转帐之类的
Please open an account for
请帮我们的40位员工
all 40 employees.
都各开一个帐户
Thank you very much.
太感谢您了
But I'm short on time.
不过我时间紧迫
We will do it immediately.
我们会立即处理
Mr. Kadowaki, the application.
门胁先生 申请书
Here's the application.
这是申请书
We'll just need ID verification for all the employees--
只需要确认每一位员工的身份证号
If you're in rush,
您如果赶时间
you can give us the verification later on.
可以之后再做确认
Just fill out this form
只要先填好表格
and submit the power of attorney.
缴交授权书
Then we will process it all at once.
我们就会一次处理完成
Are you sure?
你确定吗？
Yes, just for you, Mr. Takeuchi.
武内先生 只为您这么做
Thank you very much.
太感谢了
-Looking forward to our business. -Thank you.
-期待我们的合作 -彼此彼此
-Let me pour you a drink.
-我帮您倒酒 -谢谢
Let's eat.
吃吧
Mr. Soma,
相马先生
there's something I want to tell you.
有件事我想告诉你
What is it?
什么事？
We get some difficult customers
我们分行每天都会
at our branch every day.
来一些难搞的客人
But all of them were
不过今天他们全部都
directed toward Ms. Hanasaki today.
被引导去花琦小姐那里
Number 314.
314号
Excuse me.
抱歉
Please go to that window.
请到那个窗口
So that's what was happening.
果然是这样啊
I was noticing that
我注意到了
Hanasaki was getting yelled at a lot by the customers.
花琦被客户大吼很多次
Is Mr. Shindo one of the top management at headquarters?
真藤先生是总部的管理高层吗？
Yes.
是
He's the General Manager of Corporate Planning. Why?
他是经营企划部部长 怎么了吗？
After the bank closed, Branch Manager was
银行打烊后
talking to Mr. Kadowaki.
分行长对门胁先生说
He said, "At this rate, I can't show my face in front of Mr. Shindo."
“这样下去 我无法向真藤先生交代”
Maybe you and Ms. Hanasaki
我想你和花琦小姐
are marked by that person.
可能被那个人盯上了
What?
什么？
But that Branch Manager is so awful.
可是分行长真差劲
Saying "incompetent people are useless,"
他说这个分行不需要无能的人
and "I'm not expecting profits."
还有“我不指望你们提高利润”
That's unacceptable.
真是无法接受
-He says that all the time. -I see.
-他经常那么说 -原来如此
I want that Branch Manager to get
我希望分行长赶快调走
transferred soon. I can't handle it.
我受不了了
We don't have to worry about promotions and stuff like that,
我们不用担心升迁之类的事情
but the men must be having a tough time.
但是男人一定很辛苦
-Right? -Yeah.
-是吧？ -对
He's so busy every day.
他每天都好忙
What?
什么？
Minami's boyfriend is an ace in the Finance Department.
美波的男朋友是融资课的王牌
-Be quiet. -He's good looking too.
-嘘！ -而且是帅哥
You're so lucky! I'm so jealous.
你真幸运 我好嫉妒
-I guess work isn't all bad. -Yes.
-我猜工作也不全是坏事 -对呀
-Don't you have a picture? -He was there this morning.
-你没有他的照片吗？ -今天早上他在
I see. He's trying to gain points with Mr. Shindo
我知道了 他想靠让我和花琦不好过
by giving Hanasaki and me a hard time.
在真藤先生那里获得加分
I think so. That's why he was making you do odd jobs
我认为是这样 所以即使你是总部来的
even though you came from headquarters.
他还叫你做杂活
That Branch Manager
那个分行长
looks like he only has numbers and promotion in his head.
看起来他满脑子只有工作和升迁
Both you and Ms. Hanasaki should be careful.
你和花琦小姐都要小心
Thank you.
好
TOKYO DAIICHI BANK KAMATA BRANCH
（东京第一银行蒲田分行）
-What? -Shut up, you're so loud.
-什么？ -闭嘴 你太大声了
I'm sorry. But does that mean we were sent here to be bullied
抱歉 可是“我们是来被霸凌的” 那是什么意思？
so that the Branch Manager can get some points?
这样分行长可以得到加分是吗？
I think so. He probably thinks that Mr. Shindo will be happy
我想是的 他大概认为
if he gives us a hard time, because we took down
如果他让我们两个难过 真藤先生会开心
two members of the Shindo faction.
因为我们两个毁了真藤派两个成员
-Stop acting like a child-- -Lower your voice, idiot!
-这不是小学生行为吗？ -小声啦 笨蛋
I'm sorry.
对不起
Well, I guess I have no choice but to
那么我想我别无选择
take this challenge.
只能接受挑战
Calm down, Hanasaki. Listen. We just need to get through this day.
冷静 花琦 听好了 我们只需要过完今天
Then our job here is done.
我们在这里的工作就完成了
I will do my best today.
今天我会尽全力做好
-All right. -Will she be okay?
-很好 -她会没事吧？
I'll be at the desk instead of working as a teller?
我不做柜员 改在这张桌子工作吗？
We have lots of accounts that need to be processed.
有很多帐户需要处理
Work on this for now.
先把这些处理一下
All this by myself?
这些全部由我做 ？
Yes, do you have a problem with that?
是啊 有问题吗？
Not at all.
没有
You'll be helping the tellers too.
当然 你还要帮柜员
Sure.
是
Seriously?
不会吧？
Mr. Soma…
相马先生
It's the same old odd jobs for me.
我也是做杂活
Hurry up or you can't go home.
赶快 不然你回不了家
Yes, sir.
是
All right.
很好
-Here. -Thanks.
-麻烦你了 -谢谢
Hanasaki.
花琦
Yes.
是
-Hanasaki. -Yes.
-花琦 -是
Please do this too.
这个也请处理
Yes, sir.
是
I'm finally done.
终于做完了
Can you process the transfers now?
你现在可以处理转帐吗？
By today.
今天完成
I understand.
我知道了
Oh, I'm very sorry.
是 非常抱歉
Please wait a moment.
请稍等一下
Hanasaki, can you go to the ATM?
花琦 你可以去提款机那里吗？
What? Me?
我吗？
Can't you see that we're all busy right now?
你没看到我们都在忙吗？
I understand.
我知道了
-Hello. -Sorry.
-您好 -抱歉
Mr. Takeuchi.
武内先生
Thank you for yesterday.
昨天谢谢你
How can I help you?
需要我帮忙吗？
My passbook won't come out,
我的存折出不来
even though the cash and card came out.
钱和提款卡都出来了
I'm very sorry. I will go check on that right now,
非常抱歉 我现在就去查看
can you wait inside the lobby?
您可以在大厅等候吗？
Okay.
好
SONOKO ARAI
（新井园子）
Thank you for waiting.
让您久等了
Is this your passbook?
这是您的存折吗？
Thank you, this is my wife's. This is her maiden name.
谢谢 是我太太的 这是她结婚前的名字
I see.
这样啊
-Mr. Takeuchi. -Hello, Branch Manager.
-武内先生 -分行长 你好
Welcome. Thank you for yesterday.
欢迎 昨天谢谢您了
Likewise. And I brought some documents
我也谢谢你 我带了一些文件过来
for the application to open the accounts.
申请开户用的
Thank you.
谢谢您
For 42 people.
是42个人的
Thank you very much.
非常感谢
We will get to this right away.
我们立刻处理
I'll be leaving now.
我要先走了
I hope you weren't rude to Mr. Takeuchi.
我希望你没有对武内先生无礼
Of course not.
当然没有
That cheeky little brat hasn't changed at all.
那个厚脸皮的女孩一点都没变
She's been completing all the work I've been giving her…
我给她的工作她都完成了
What are you doing?
你搞什么啊？
Then we'll do whatever it takes
那么无论如何
to take her down a peg or two.
我们都要挫挫她的锐气
-Here it is. -Okay.
-麻烦你了 -好的
I wonder if I can finish this today.
不知道今天能不能做完
This is the payment from a customer at the Finance Department.
这是融资课一位客户的付款
-Process it. -Yes, sir.
-先处理它 -是
He's almost leaving, so do it right away.
他就要离开了 立刻处理
Yes, sir.
是
What?
什么？
Writing the account number is basic routine.
写帐号是基本程序
Unbelievable.
真不敢相信
AKASHI BUILDING
（明石营造）
SEARCH
（搜索）
What have you done?
你搞什么啊？
I'm sorry.
很抱歉
We asked you to request a deposit from Akashi Building Inc.
要你向明石营造股份有限公司 要求押金
But you sent a request to Akashi Building Ltd.
你却向明石营造有限责任公司 提出要求
They're different companies.
他们是不同的公司
The account number wasn't written on the deposit slip,
因为存款单上没有写帐号
so I searched for it myself.
所以我就自己搜寻了
I didn't know there were two companies with the same name.
我不知道这两间公司的名字一样
What?
什么？
You're blaming it on the deposit slip?
你怪到存款单上？
No…
不是
Mr. Kadowaki noticed the error
门胁先生注意到了
and stopped it from
才没继续错下去
getting processed, so it didn't become a big issue.
才没有演变成大问题
But what if he didn't notice it?
万一他没注意到呢？
How embarrassing.
多丢脸啊
Even a rookie wouldn't
就算是菜鸟
make an error with the account number, right?
也不会犯帐号的错误 对吧？
Yes.
对
Our branch was about to get marked up
我们分行差一点就要被扣分了
because of someone who's only here for two days.
因为某个才到这里两天的人
I'm very sorry.
我非常抱歉
Don't just apologize to me. Apologize to everyone else.
不要只对我道歉 对所有人道歉
I'm very sorry
造成大家的困扰
for causing you trouble.
我非常抱歉
Listen everyone.
都听好了
You guys better not make an embarrassing mistake like this.
你们最好不要犯下这么丢脸的错误
We don't need incompetent people in this branch.
这个分行不需要无能的人
Just as I promised, I taught them a nice lesson.
和我承诺的一样 让他们好好上了一课
Thank you.
谢谢你
I'm sure it will make Mr. Shindo very happy.
相信真藤部长会非常高兴
I'm very sorry
真的很抱歉
for causing trouble for you.
给你们造成困扰
Don't be. That was definitely a trap.
不用道歉 那绝对是陷阱
-A trap? -Everyone at this branch knows.
-陷阱？ -这个分行里的每一个人
About there being two companies
都知道有两家公司
called Akashi Building.
叫做明石营造
-What? -It's easy to mistake them.
-什么？ -很容易搞错
So Mr. Kadowaki is always telling us not to forget
所以门胁先生总是叫我们别忘了
the account number on the slip.
在单子上写下帐号
-Then… -He did it on purpose.
-那么… -他是故意的
So that you would fail.
好让你出错
If they stop it in time,
如果他们及时阻止
our branch won't get in trouble.
我们分行就不会有麻烦
I doubt Mr. Kadowaki could do that on his own initiative,
我怀疑门胁先生有办法自己做到
so it must have been set up by the Branch Manager.
一定是分行长设计的
RESTAURANT HANASAKI
（花琦居酒屋）
I was completely tricked.
我完全被设计了
That's why he looked so smug.
所以他才那么沾沾自喜
That damn Branch Manager!
那个可恶的分行长
It's delicious.
真好吃
Mr. Soma, were you listening to what I was saying?
相马先生 你有在听我说话吗？
Let's forget about it, since it's all behind us now.
忘了吧 反正都过去了
But still…
可是
I feel bad for everyone working there too.
我替每个在那里工作的人感到难过
They have to work under that Branch Manager.
他们不得不在那个分行长手下做事
The performance at Kamata Branch is declining,
蒲田分行的绩效在下降
but that's definitely Branch Manager Suga's fault.
那肯定是须贺分行长的过错
Yeah. No one would have the motivation to work when
也对 他践踏大家的尊严
he strips everyone of their dignity.
没有人会有工作动力
Is he really an elite?
他真的是精英吗？
Being capable or not,
有没有能力
and having good leadership or not
和有没有领导力
are two different things.
是两回事
I see. Which means he's disqualified as a Branch Manager.
我懂了 表示他是不称职的分行长
I didn't go that far.
我没说到那个地步
Isn't there anything we can do?
没有什么是我们能做的吗？
If you keep on empathizing with the branch employees,
如果你还是每次都同情分行柜员
it'll make it that much harder for you to continue this job.
会让你更难做这份工作
Fine.
好吧
What? Are you serious?
什么 你说真的吗？
-Yes. -Oh no. I got tricked.
-对 是假货 -不 我被骗了
-What happened, Dad? -Listen, Mai.
-爸 怎么啦？ -听着 小舞
This supplement is a scam.
这个营养补剂是诈骗
-What? -A scam?
-什么？ -诈骗？
I guess it was a hot topic online
我猜它是网络上的热门话题
because they received a flood of complaints. I was tricked.
因为他们收到一大堆投诉 我被骗了
-Oh no. -That's horrible.
-哎呀 -太可恶了
Someone researched the ingredients
有人研究了它的成分
and found nothing effective in it. It's like candy.
发现没一样有效 它就像糖果
No one can contact them anymore.
没有人联系得上他们
They probably fled already.
他们大概早就跑了
They fled…
跑了
Can I see that?
那个可以让我看看吗？
Sure.
当然
Araiso no Ko.
“荒矶之子”
BANK NAME - TOKYO DAIICHI BANK BRANCH - ASAGAYA BRANCH
（阿佐谷分行）
Hey, their account is our bank at the Asagaya Branch.
喂 他们的银行帐号 是我们在阿佐谷区的分行
You're right.
真的
That means our bank account was used for illegal dealings.
那表示我们的银行帐号 被用来进行非法交易
Well, only if it really was a scam.
除非它真的是诈欺
Hey Mai,
小舞
wouldn't your bank be able to find the culprit?
你们银行不能查到这个罪犯吗？
Report it to the police.
向警方报案
-That's not possible. -Why?
-那是不可能的 -为什么？
People use dummy accounts for illegal dealings.
他们会用人头帐号做非法交易
-Dummy accounts? -They use other people's names.
-人头帐户？ -使用别人的名字
Or they make up names
或者编造假名字
to trick the bank into opening an account.
骗过银行开设帐户
Even the bank doesn't know who's using the account.
连银行都不知道是谁在使用那个帐户
-It's a big problem. -Oh, so it's used for scams.
-那是大问题 -所以它被用于
All sorts of them?
各种诈骗吗？
-I've seen those before. -That's right.
-那些我以前见过 -就是这样
As a bank, we can't stop such transactions,
我们银行是无法阻止这样的交易
so it's difficult to handle.
所以很难处理
How frustrating.
真泄气
You know that it's a scam,
知道是诈骗
but you can't catch them!
却不能抓他们
What is it?
怎么了？
Mr. Soma, we may be able to catch this con artist.
相马先生 我们也许可以抓到这个诈骗犯
What?
什么？
SONOKO ARAI
（新井园子）
SEARCH
（搜寻）
Just as I thought.
跟我想的一样
What do you mean?
这是什么意思？
-Mr. Soma, look at this. -What?
-相马先生 你来看 -看什么？
The name under this account
这个帐户的户名
is not Araiso no Ko,
不是“荒矶之子”
but Sonoko Arai.
而是“新井园子”
SONOKO ARAI
（新井园子）
Oh.
哦
The scam artist who made this dummy account
开这个人头户的诈骗犯
decided to scam people by
决定用这个名字
making supplements using this name.
制造营养补剂骗人
They're both the same in katakana.
它们的片假名是一样的
Transfers use katakana,
利用新井园子转帐
so he used that to his advantage.
他就是利用这一点
I see.
原来如此
People would find it suspicious to transfer money to an actual person,
将钱转给真的人 大家会起疑
but this made it look like it was the company name.
但是这样就看起来就像公司名了
Just like my dad.
我爸也被骗了
I have to say, it's a smart idea but…
不得不说这是个聪明的点子
Wait, didn't you say that we might
等等 你不是说
be able to catch this con artist?
也许可以抓到诈骗犯吗？
Who is it?
诈骗犯是谁？
Mr. Takeuchi.
武内先生
Mr. Takeuchi…
武内先生？
-The customer at Kamata Branch? -Yes.
-什么？那个蒲田分行的客户？ -对
Yesterday I saw…
昨天我看到了
Mr. Takeuchi with the passbook for this account.
武内先生带着这个户名的存折
It's my wife's.
是我太太的
Mr. Takeuchi said that it was his wife's passbook,
武内先生说那是他太太的存折
but she had a different last name.
但是她的姓不一样
Are you serious?
你是说真的吗？
Mr. Takeuchi is the con artist, right?
武内先生是诈骗犯 对吧？
It seems so…
看起来是这样
Oh no, this is bad.
不 不好了
Yesterday, they processed all
昨天他们帮武内先生
42 bank accounts for Mr. Takeuchi's employees.
处理了42个员工的银行帐户
-What? -He had the power of attorney,
-什么？ -他有授权书
but no personal verification.
但是没有个人验证
But the Branch Manager pushed it through.
可是分行长强行通过
If those are all dummy accounts to be used for fraud…
如果那些都是用来诈骗的人头帐户
This is awful.
那可糟了
Let's go talk to Mr. Takeuchi.
我们去找武内先生谈谈
Yeah.
好
Is it really here?
真的是在这里吗？
It should be close by.
应该很靠近了
It should be around the corner.
应该就在附近
What?
什么？
Here are the 42 passbooks.
全部42本存折都在这里了
Thank you very much.
非常感谢
Wait a minute!
等一下
What are you doing here?
你们来这里做什么？
-Do not give him the passbooks. -What are you doing?
-别把存折给他 -你想干嘛？
How dare you be so rude.
你竟敢这么无礼
-Give it back. -Mr. Takeuchi, I'm very sorry.
-还回来 -武内先生 我非常抱歉
Mr. Takeuchi, where is your company located?
武内先生 你的公司在哪里？
What?
什么？
We just went to the address where your company is supposed to be.
我们刚刚去了你公司应该在的地址
The place was just a small park.
那个地方只是一个小公园
What's this nonsense?
胡说八道什么？
It's not nonsense.
不是胡说八道
Mr. Takeuchi,
武内先生
you are a con artist.
你是诈骗犯
There is no relocation or a company to begin with.
根本就没有公司搬迁
ARAISO NO KO
（荒矶之子）
You got in contact with the Branch Manager in order to make
你接触分行长
dummy accounts for your fraud.
是想开设诈骗用的人头帐户
The name Katsumi Takeuchi is most likely
武内克美这个名字
a fake name.
很可能也是假名
What is your real name?
你的真名叫什么？
POLICE DEPARTMENT
（警察局）
This is unbelievable.
真是难以置信
I can't believe Mr. Takeuchi was a con artist.
我无法相信武内先生是诈骗犯
What's going to happen to our branch?
我们分行会怎么样？
Let's go, Hanasaki.
走吧 花琦
Yes.
好
The Branch Manager and I will go to the police for some questioning.
我和分行长要去警局回答问题
You have nothing to worry about.
你们没什么好担心的
Because as far as this incident is concerned, we are the victims.
因为就这个案子考量 我们是受害者
Let's go, Branch Manager.
走吧 分行长
Branch Manager?
分行长？
Why do I have to deal with this?
我为什么要面对这件事？
This is all your fault!
都是你们的错！
If you had brought results,
如果你们有做出成果
we wouldn't have fallen for that dumb scam.
我们就不会落入那个愚蠢的骗局
How dare you taint my career!
你们竟敢玷污我的职业生涯
-I'm sorry. -Sorry.
-对不起
-Wait a minute. -Hey…
-等一下！ -等等
The one who fell for that "damn scam"
落入那个愚蠢骗局的人
is you, Branch Manager.
是你 须贺分行长
What?
说什么？
It's wrong to blame your employees for that.
怪罪你的员工是不对的
Don't you dare talk to me like that.
你竟敢这样对我说话！
Do you know how much I've suffered
你知道我为了这些无能的人
because of these incompetent people?
受了多少罪吗？
With all due respect…
恕我直言
everyone here is not incompetent.
这里没有无能的人
Didn't you think that they would lose the meaning of work when you
你每天那样斥责他们
berate them like that every day?
你不认为他们会失去工作的动力吗？
The performance at this branch is bad
这个分行的业绩不好
because the atmosphere of the workplace is bad.
是因为工作场所的气氛不好
What are you saying?
你在说什么？
-Shut up! -No, I won't.
-闭嘴！ -我不要！
You only think about your promotion
你只想到自己的升迁
and silence your subordinates.
还要你的下属默不作声
That's wrong!
那是错的
You always say
你总是说
that incompetent people are not needed here.
这里不需要无能的人
If that's so,
如果是那样
what this branch doesn't need
这间分行不需要的
is you, Branch Manager Suga.
是分行长须贺先生你
I'm sorry for causing a scene.
对不起 我大呼小叫的
What?
什么？
Oh… um…
那个…
it's not worthy of applause…
不值得鼓掌吧？
Ms. Hanasaki, look at all this.
花琦小姐 你看看
My heart is beating so fast…
我的心跳好快
You were so cool.
你好酷
He was caught.
他被抓了
SUSPECT SUZUKI
（嫌疑犯铃木浩）
He looks like a bad guy.
他看起来就是坏人
I hope I can catch the bus.
希望能赶上公车
Here you go, Dad.
爸 这个给你
-I'll be off. -Okay, bye.
-我出门了 -好 再见
What?
什么啊？
ENERGETIC AND LIVELY! FRESH HEALTHY EXERCISE
（元气活力健康操）
That girl…
那个孩子…
Branch Manager Suga's next transfer will most likely be to the countryside.
须贺分行长下次最有可能调去乡下
I think so too.
我也这么想
Banks are tough.
银行好难
That's right. I've worked hard until now enduring hardships
没错 我一直努力到现在
one after another as I was sandwiched between my boss
夹在上司与下属中间
and my subordinate…
忍受着一个又一个的磨难
-What? -Oh no!
-怎样？ -糟糕
I had compliance training today.
我今天要参加合规培训
-I might not make in time. -Give me a break.
-我可能没办法准时到 -帮帮忙吧
They'll blame me for management issues.
他们会怪我管理不当
-I'm sorry. -That's right, Hanasaki.
-抱歉 -没错 花琦
If you can't fulfill your schedule, or be on time, it's an issue.
你如果无法履行你的日程安排 或无法准时 那是问题
-Not just as a banker but-- -Sorry, I'll be off.
-不只是当银行职员 而且… -抱歉 我要走了
She never listens to other people.
她从来不把别人的话听完
Sorry.
真是抱歉
I'm very sorry. I didn't imagine such a thing would happen.
我非常抱歉 我没想到会发生这样的事
It's fine.
没关系
Those two prevented our bank from embarrassing itself
那两个人成功阻止了我们银行
by opening dummy accounts.
开设人头帐户的过错
But Kodama…
但是儿玉…
Yes, sir.
是
I…
我
hate words that display
讨厌那些字眼
weakness…
弱点
Error.
错误
Loss.
亏损
Failure!
失败！
BRANCH INSPECTION
（分行稽核班）
I can't pass up on the eel.
我不能错过鳗鱼
What is it now?
现在又是怎样？
The training was tomorrow.
培训是明天
-Hey. -Sorry.
-喂！ -对不起
Disappeared?
失踪？
It's your fault my son disappeared.
我儿子失踪是你们的错
It's like the monster parents.
就是所谓的怪兽父母
No financing?
我们等这么久只得到拒绝贷款吗？
I'm sorry.
很可惜 我帮不了你们
There's something off about Branch Manager Nakamura.
中村分行长肯定有问题
Loving your child doesn't give you the right
爱孩子并没有赋予你
to do whatever you want.
为所欲为的权利
Subtitle translation by: Lili Morita
字幕翻译：李怡朴